Guide to the Bernhard Knollenberg Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence (Chronological), 1560-1943; Series I; 5.5 linear feet (13 Boxes)
  - ALS, Justice B.R. Curtis to Daniel Mills regarding several court cases, 1850 July 1 (Box 9, Folder 757)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; pardon of Hiram Nash, 1850 July 16 (Box 9, Folder 758)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; burglary at Baron's, Nash's testimony, 1850 August 5 (Box 9, Folder 759)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; rising problems with sectionalism, 1850 August 10 (Box 9, Folder 760)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; notice of pardon of Nash, 1850 August 12 (Box 9, Folder 761)
  - ALS, N.M. Bigler to Tyler (Gov. of Pa.); candidacy, factional fights, 1850 August 14 (Box 9, Folder 762)
  - ALS, Alvah Hunt to Charles C.P. Clark; questioning Fish's letter on name, 1850 August (Box 9, Folder 763)
  - ALS, Millard Fillmore to Isaac McDonald; explanation of appointment of Dorr instead of McDonald, 1850 October 25 (Box 9, Folder 764)
  - ALS, Winthrop Bailey to Rev. Bernard Whitman; religious matters and organizations, 1850 October 25 (Box 9, Folder 765)
  - ALS, Washington Hunt to Alvah Hunt; opposed by Seymour--Fugitive Slave Law, 1850 October 31 (Box 9, Folder 766)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; case of Harris, 1850 November 1 (Box 9, Folder 767)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; confidential --regarding possible deserters from political circle, 1850 November 4 (Box 9, Folder 768)
  - ALS, Washington Hunt to Alvah Hunt; appointment suggestions for Judge Advocate General, 1850 December 30 (Box 9, Folder 769)
  - Incomplete diary of Henry Hoover; Photostatic Copy. (Complete photostat -book CM 38.0170), 1850 (Box 9, Folder 770)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Alvah Hunt; asks Hunt to recommend O.F. Wright, 1851 January 12 (Box 9, Folder 771)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; asks Hunt to look over some papers, 1851 January 29 (Box 9, Folder 772)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; recounts discussion with Tarnum, (?), 1851 February 1 (Box 9, Folder 773)
  - ALS, F. Lieber to Ruggles; inquiry about Samuel Griffin, 1851 February 23 (Box 9, Folder 774)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; problems with majority in Assembly, 1851 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 775)
  - ALS, Washington Hunt to Alvah Hunt; canal tolls, 1851 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 776)
  - AD, Debt of Lockport Bk, 1851 March 29 (Box 9, Folder 777)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; various news including comment on Root, taxes, 1851 March 31 (Box 9, Folder 778)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; regarding removal of Mr. Hall from office, 1851 April 4 (Box 9, Folder 779)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; switches in voting, 1851 June 21 (Box 9, Folder 781)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; caucus of legislators on reapportionment, 1851 July 5 (Box 9, Folder 782)
  - ALS, N.N. Curtis to Daniel Bell; comments on taking office, 1851 October 3 (Box 9, Folder 783)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; regarding piece of jewelry, 1851 November 14 (Box 9, Folder 784)
  - ALS, Edward Scofield to "friend"; news of family, recent plans, 1852 February 17 (Box 9, Folder 785)
  - ALS, Lewis Cass to O.S. Day; regarding Col. Pease(?), 1852 April 10 (Box 9, Folder 786)
  - Autographs of Lewis Cass, undated (Box 9, Folder 787)
  - Photographs of Lewis Cass, undated (Box 9, Folder 788)
  - ALS, Dorothea Dix to Miss Arnold; various philanthropic topics, 1852 July 10 (Box 9, Folder 789)
  - ALS, Horatio Seymour to (?); request for job for friend, 1852 August 13 (Box 9, Folder 790)
  - ALS, Alex H. Stuart (Sec. of Interior) to W. Wallach; decision against examination of letters of recommendation, 1852 November 20 (Box 9, Folder 791)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; news of Albany, few left of "brotherhood.", 1852 December 7 (Box 9, Folder 792)
  - ALS, Dorothea Dix to Miss Arnold; deaf causes, 1852 December 21 (Box 9, Folder 793)
  - Narrative of Col. James speech explaining vote for Buchanan and split from Whigs, 1852 (Box 9, Folder 794)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; Erie affair, 1853 January 1 (Box 9, Folder 795)
  - ALS, M. Pierpont to George D. Wells; accepts invitation to lecture, 1853 January 7 (Box 9, Folder 796)
  - ALS, Horatio Southgate to F. W. Hune, 1853 January 24 (Box 9, Folder 797)
  - ALS, George Grote to Churchill Babington; regarding Greek tragedians and writers, 1853 February 1 (Box 9, Folder 798)
  - ALS, Edward Everett to W. H. Gardiner; Chile--property, neutrality, 1853 February 14 (Box 9, Folder 799)
  - ALS, Jeremiah Biggs to Ernest Jones; loan, House of Commons, 1853 February 28 (Box 9, Folder 800)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; situation (political) in Albany, 1853 April 3 (Box 9, Folder 801)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; relection of the Senate, 1853 May 18 (Box 9, Folder 802)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; Fillmore administration, Whigs, 1853 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 803)
  - Autograph of Millard Fillmore sent to unknown requestent, 1853 July 11 (Box 9, Folder 804)
  - ALS, J.F. Reujanin to Mr. Bourwell; regarding $100 organization, 1853 July 12 (Box 9, Folder 805)
  - Printed circular "Collecting Fish" by L. Agassiz, sent to H. Haupt, 1853 October 8 (Box 9, Folder 806)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; caucus, desire to leave Senate, 1853 December 13 (Box 9, Folder 807)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; Erie riots, failure of Congress to act, 1854 January 4 (Box 9, Folder 808)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; conflict of interest, railroad matters, 1854 May 8 (Box 9, Folder 809)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; problems with mail, 1854 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 810)
  - Patents issued to Eli Coon, land title explanation by Robert Holdsworth (descendent), 1855 March 3 (Box 9, Folder 811)
  - ALS, J. A Froude to Parker; acknowledgement of cheque, 1855 April 5 (Box 9, Folder 812)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; canals, fish, 1855 May 11 (Box 9, Folder 813)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; asks Hunt to examine material, 1855 May 28 (Box 9, Folder 814)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; Abell's reaction to Hunt's letter, 1855 August 30 (Box 9, Folder 815)
  - ALS, John B. Floyd to (?); property, oil, 1855 November 20 (Box 9, Folder 816)
  - ALS, Edward Everett to Charles C. Perkins; Mercantile Library Association celebration, 1856 January 31 (Box 9, Folder 817)
  - ALS, John Torrey to M. Gilliss; regarding receipt of volumes by various groups, 1856 February 19 (Box 9, Folder 818)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Emma Neuhold; regarding teachers for Mrs. Greeley, 1856 March 2 (Box 9, Folder 819)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Emma Neuhold; regarding split between states, 1856 May 16 (Box 9, Folder 820)
  - ALS, Ch. Gounod to Jules Simon; (French) list of names and addresses, 1856 July 1 (Box 9, Folder 821)
  - ALS, Emilias W. Babcock to "Paul"; sale of books in Midwest, 1856 October 5 (Box 9, Folder 822)
  - ALS, G.F. Davis to W.H. Davis (brother); description of life in "frontier.", 1856 October 8 (Box 9, Folder 823)
  - ALS, C. Wilkes to Mon. Alex Vattemare; publication of two charts, 1856 November 15 (Box 9, Folder 824)
  - ALS, J.C. Fremont to C.W. Elliott; requests return of book loaned to him, 1856 [?] (Box 9, Folder 825)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Emma Neuhold; regarding planting, costs, 1857 January 11 (Box 9, Folder 826)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Alvah Hunt; regarding libel suit, 1857 May 1 (Box 9, Folder 827)
  - ALS, Edward Everett to Henry L. Randall; request for return of his letters of political nature, 1857 September 2 (Box 9, Folder 828)
  - ALS, Capt. M.C. Meigs to Mr. Davis; various political questions, 1857 October 30 (Box 9, Folder 829)
  - ALS, Jus. V. Liebig to "colleague"; confirmation of time of lecture, picture of Liebig, 1857 November 21 (Box 9, Folder 830)
  - ALS, F.D. Huntington to [?]; publication of book, 1857 November 22 (Box 9, Folder 831)
  - ALS, Samuel Howe to [?]; regarding two translations, 1858 February 8 (Box 9, Folder 832)
  - ALS, Philip Allen (Gov. of R.I.) to brother; reminiscences, present activities, 1858 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 833)
  - ALS, Alexander Stephens to G.F. Buston; five checks--explanations, 1858 December 20 (Box 9, Folder 834)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to P. Fependez; various foreign ministries, Seward, 1859 January 6 (Box 9, Folder 835)
  - ALS, William Seward to C.C. Clarke; death of Alvah Hunt, 1859 March 17 (Box 9, Folder 836)
  - ALS, F.E. Spinner (Treas. of U.S.) to Willis Patten; regarding Harbor Masters, new sewing machine, 1859 April 9 (Box 9, Folder 837)
  - ALS, Edward Everett to Gov. Banks; refusal of invitation to review militia at Concord, 1859 September 6 (Box 9, Folder 838)
  - ALS, F. Manry to Mr. George H. Hill; United States reversal, 1860 April 9 (Box 9, Folder 839)
  - ALS, J. Washburn to Thurlow Weed; solicit support for nomination of Patten, 1860 July 20 (Box 9, Folder 840)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to ["friend]; news of recent activities, letters owed to him, 1861 October 1 (Box 9, Folder 842)
  - ALS, L. Agassiz to S.A. Stevens; letter of introduction, 1860 October 3 (Box 9, Folder 843)
  - ALS, Joseph Henry to T. Allen; regarding account of Roger Williams, 1860 November 9 (Box 9, Folder 844)
  - Original draft of papers, "Slave Property in the Territories" written to Gen. Gazette (newspaper)for slavery, 1860 (ca.) (Box 9, Folder 845)
  - ALS, William Seward to Pheggs and Company; regarding Treasury notes, 1861 January 19 (Box 9, Folder 846)
  - ALS, August Belmont to Simon Cameron; request for consideration of William Slidell, 1861 May 13 (Box 9, Folder 847)
  - ALS, Daniel S. Dickinson to Gilman; visit to farm, 1861 October 17 (Box 9, Folder 848)
  - ALS, Daniel, S. Dickinson to Ira F. Haith; agreement to lecture for group, 1861 October 31 (Box 9, Folder 849)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to Mrs. Joanna Curtiss; sickness of friend, 1861 November 31 (Box 9, Folder 850)
  - ALS, L. Agassiz to M.M. Bagg; accepts invitation to stay at home, 1861 December 10 (Box 9, Folder 851)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to Curtiss; Civil War regiment news, health, 1862 February 13 (Box 10, Folder 852)
  - ALS, Daniel S. Dickinson to J.F. Hart; failure to be able to help, 1862 March 28 (Box 10, Folder 853)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to [?] Curtiss; Pulaski captured, 1862 April 15 (Box 10, Folder 854)
  - ALS, W.R. Harley to President Abraham Lincoln; recommendation of Frigg to fill judgeship, 1862 July 14 (Box 10, Folder 855)
  - ALS, Simon Cameron to C.A. Walforn; news of War received, 1862 July 21 (Box 10, Folder 856)
  - ALS, Daniel Dickinson to J. A. Folver [?] Chess; circular attacking Seward, 1862 July 26 (Box 10, Folder 857)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to Mrs. Curtiss; thinks War is near its close, 1862 August 1 (Box 10, Folder 858)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; news of War, recent activities, uniform, 1862 August 22 (Box 10, Folder 859)
  - ALS, Reverdy Johnson to Gen. H.W. Slocum; protection, daughter, 1862 August 22 (Box 10, Folder 860)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; description of men in company, 1862 August 24 (Box 10, Folder 861)
  - ALS, S. Cox to Frank A. [Smenif]; regarding support in campaign, 1862 September 2 (Box 10, Folder 862)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to Mrs. Curtiss; son's joining army, death of slavery, 1862 September 3 (Box 10, Folder 863)
  - ALS, Homer S. Curtiss to mother (Joanna); Stonewall Jackson, 1862 September 4 (Box 10, Folder 864)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; sending extra supplies home, 1862 September 8 (Box 10, Folder 865)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Seth Reynolds; description of regiment, 1862 September 12 (Box 10, Folder 866)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; shipping out for South, sent money home, 1862 September 13 (Box 10, Folder 867)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss. to family; relates moving to Burlington, 1862 September 16 (Box 10, Folder 868)
  - ALS, Homer Curtis to family; traveling with troops, 1862 September 17 (Box 10, Folder 869)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to Aunt Jean; Maryland action, 1862 September 17 (Box 10, Folder 870)
  - ALS, Gov. Thomas Seymour to N. Capon; letter wanted, Troy Convention, 1862 September 18 (Box 10, Folder 871)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; discouraged by War, 1862 September 25-October 4 (Box 10, Folder 872)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; writing letters for those who can't, 1862 October 7 (Box 10, Folder 873)
  - ALS, Seth Reynolds to Mrs. Curtiss; fatigue, poor living conditions, 1862 October 11 (Box 10, Folder 874)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to [?]; description of tent, 1862 October 11 (Box 10, Folder 875)
  - ADS, Col. Walter Burnham; pass for Homer S. Curtiss, 1862 October 16 (Box 10, Folder 876)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; inquiry whether received material sent home, 1862 October 19 (Box 10, Folder 877)
  - ALS, Alfred Hatch to Homer Curtiss; death of Seth Reynolds, 1862 October 23 (Box 10, Folder 878)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; death of Seth Reynolds, 1862 November 8 (Box 10, Folder 879)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; guarding hospital tent, 1862 November 16 (Box 10, Folder 880)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sister; setting up headquarters, 1862 November 18 (Box 10, Folder 881)
  - ALS, Francis Lieber to [?]; regarding historical research, 1862 November 19 (Box 10, Folder 882)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sisters; poor conditions of camp, arms, 1862 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 883)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; thinks war will end within year, 1862 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 884)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; news of people in regiment from home, 1862 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 885)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; who he likes in regiment, 1862 November 24 (Box 10, Folder 886)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; sickness, 1862 November 28 (Box 10, Folder 887)
  - ALS, Dennis Lossing to Joshua Cohn; publication of sketches in "Harper's", 1862 December 2 (Box 10, Folder 888)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; sending things he doesn't need to family, 1862 December 17 (Box 10, Folder 889)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to brother; thanks for food at home; news of friends, 1863 January 7 (Box 10, Folder 890)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; no sign of leaving camp, 1863 January 7 (Box 10, Folder 891)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; drill, sickness in regiment, 1863 January 8 (Box 10, Folder 892)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; good morale, entertain each other in camp, 1863 January 17 (Box 10, Folder 893)
  - LSA, H. Foote to Comm. C.L. Stribling; articles under control of Bureau of Navigation, 1863 January 22 (Box 10, Folder 894)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; death of several friends, 1863 January 25 (Box 10, Folder 895)
  - ALS, A.H. Foote to C.K. Stribling; refusal to approve requisition for men, 1863 January 28 (Box 10, Folder 896)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; possibility of furlough, 1863 February 12 (Box 10, Folder 897)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sisters; high cost of food and tea, no chaplain, 1863 February 19 (Box 10, Folder 898)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; snowball fight in camp, 1863 March 1 (Box 10, Folder 899)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; reflections on birthday and effects of war, 1863 March 7 (Box 10, Folder 900)
  - ALS, William Baldwin to John H. James; taking care of affairs of James who is sick, 1863 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 901)
  - ALS, William Baldwin to Miss Ellen James; enclose letter from brother, 1863 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 902)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; discouraged and not well, 1863 March 22 (Box 10, Folder 903)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; sick with mumps, 1863 March 28 (Box 10, Folder 904)
  - ALS, Flora Humphrey to Austin Humphrey; friends she has made, plans to visit, 1863 March 30 (Box 10, Folder 905)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; sending money home, 1863 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 906)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; decision not to take furlough, 1863 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 907)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; Col. Kellogg leaves after disagreement, 1863 April 3 (Box 10, Folder 908)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; possibility of merge of regiment with another, 1863 April 8 (Box 10, Folder 909)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; word of riots in South, 1863 April 9 (Box 10, Folder 910)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; Austin Humphrey, 1863 April 16 (Box 10, Folder 911)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; armed artillery drill, 1863 April 18 (Box 10, Folder 912)
  - DS, Certification of squad's freedom from smoking, 1863 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 913)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to sisters; hauling guns, wagons, 1863 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 914)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; death of a friend, 1863 April 29 (Box 10, Folder 915)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; friend's eyes failing, 1863 May 6 (Box 10, Folder 916)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; disorganization of camp, 1863 May 12 (Box 10, Folder 917)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; does not contemplate great future for army, 1863 May 14 (Box 10, Folder 918)
  - ALS, L.S. to Thomas [?]; in poor health, trip to Jefferson, 1863 May 15 (Box 10, Folder 919)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; regarding pictures of friends, 1863 May 21 (Box 10, Folder 920)
  - ADS, W. Perry to Company; pass for commissary, 1863 May 25 (Box 10, Folder 921)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; pass to Washington, 1863 May 26 (Box 10, Folder 922)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; death of Flora Humphrey, 1863 June 7 (Box 10, Folder 923)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; return of Col. Kellogg, 1863 June 11 (Box 10, Folder 924)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; progress of Hooker, 1863 June 16 (Box 10, Folder 925)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; communications cut at Havre de Grace, 1863 June 18 (Box 10, Folder 926)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; Hooker withdrawn, now at front of fighting, 1863 June 25 (Box 10, Folder 927)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; better attitude toward Black enlistees, 1863 June (Box 10, Folder 928)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; Vicksburg, 1863 July 8 (Box 10, Folder 929)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; orders pair of boots, 1863 July 14 (Box 10, Folder 930)
  - ADS, C,J, Deming; orders-countersign for day, 1863 July 17 (Box 10, Folder 931)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; more conscripts added to regiment, 1863 July 18 (Box 10, Folder 932)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; relative merits of Meade, Hooker and Burnside, 1863 July 19 (Box 10, Folder 933)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; various officers' actions, 1863 July 28 (Box 10, Folder 934)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; sick, fever, 1863 July 30 (Box 10, Folder 935)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; army needs reinforcements, 1863 August 13 (Box 10, Folder 936)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; regiment well drilled, 1863 August 26 (Box 10, Folder 937)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; promotions, 1863 August 29 (Box 10, Folder 938)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; regarding failure of romance, 1863 August (Box 10, Folder 939)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; one year in army, 1863 September 10 (Box 10, Folder 940)
  - ADS, C.D. Cleveland; pass for John Harrington Wagoner, 1863 September 11 (Box 10, Folder 941)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; inspection of troops, 1863 September 13 (Box 10, Folder 942)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; description of country, 1863 September 18 (Box 10, Folder 943)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; sickness of friends, 1863 September 28 (Box 10, Folder 944)
  - DS, Rollin C. Gate (Capt.); pass for Homer Curtiss, 1863 September 9 (Box 10, Folder 945)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; inspections, battle, 1863 October 9 (Box 10, Folder 946)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; call for more men, 1863 October 19 (Box 10, Folder 947)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; trips to Alexandria, 1863 October 20 (Box 10, Folder 948)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; regarding "Laura", 1863 October 24 (Box 10, Folder 949)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; trip to Fort Reynolds for court martial, 1863 October 29 (Box 10, Folder 950)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; sick from fever and chills, 1863 November 7 (Box 10, Folder 951)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; patient in hospital, 1863 November 11 (Box 10, Folder 952)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss; includes menu, 1863 November 12 (Box 10, Folder 953)
  - ALS, A. Ledgewick to D.; trial, 1863 November 27 (Box 10, Folder 954)
  - ALS, G.W. Gitlin to Wm. Taxan; recommendation for Austin, 1863 December 3 (Box 10, Folder 955)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; regarding stay in hospital, 1863 December 10 (Box 10, Folder 956)
  - ADS, J. Wesley Smith to Joseph Sheffield; twenty volumes of Natural History of State (Albany), 1863 December 11 (Box 10, Folder 957)
  - DS, Pass for J. Gridley to Alexandria, 1863 December 14 (Box 10, Folder 958)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; wasteful practices of army, 1863 December 14 (Box 10, Folder 959)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fanny Curtiss; news of camp and friends, 1863 December 17 (Box 10, Folder 960)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; description of camp, 1863 December 25 (Box 10, Folder 961)
  - DS, J.B. Anderson; special requisition slips, 1863 (Box 10, Folder 962)
  - ALS, S.P. Chase to Frank Rions; request for copies, 1863 (Box 10, Folder 963)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; keeping general financial records, 1864 January 3 (Box 10, Folder 964)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; army of the Cumberland, 1864 January 27 (Box 10, Folder 965)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; desire for furlough, 1864 February 4 (Box 10, Folder 966)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; Austin Humphrey home, 1864 February 4 (Box 10, Folder 967)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; desertion of men in company, 1864 February 8 (Box 10, Folder 968)
  - ALS, Robert Winthrop to Prof. Gould; regarding rule changes for academy, 1864 February 8 (Box 10, Folder 969)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; urges sister to be kind to Austin Humphrey, 1864 March 3 (Box 10, Folder 970)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; urges sister not to judge the soldiers, 1864 March 7 (Box 10, Folder 971)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; changes in officers, 1864 March 19 (Box 10, Folder 972)
  - ALS, Sgt. "Tub" (Homer Curtiss) to family; rumours of marching orders, 1864 March 31 (Box 10, Folder 973)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; poor living conditions and morale, 1864 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 974)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; captain's commission, 1864 April 4 (Box 10, Folder 975)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; news from home, 1864 April 12 (Box 10, Folder 976)
  - ALS, Homer Curtis to "Pete"; sick with fever and ague, 1864 April 18 (Box 10, Folder 977)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; poor health of Col. Smith, 1864 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 978)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; transfer of sick to home hospitals, 1864 April 21 (Box 10, Folder 979)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; warning about romantic entanglements, 1864 May 2 (Box 10, Folder 980)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to O.D. Case; regarding publication of volumes, 1864 May 6 (Box 10, Folder 981)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; Grant at Chancellersville, 1864 May 8 (Box 10, Folder 982)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; no sign of moving out, 1864 June 3 (Box 11, Folder 983)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; details of battle at Richmond, 1864 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 984)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; account of Army of the Potomac, 1864 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 985)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to mother; off to front, 1864 June 13 (Box 11, Folder 986)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to Fannie Curtiss; description of movement of Army, 1864 June 21 (Box 11, Folder 987)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; lull in fighting., 1864 June 26 (Box 11, Folder 988)
  - ALS, Homer Curtiss to family; description of camp, 1864 July 2 (Box 11, Folder 989)